Guide to the Office of Institutional Research, Yale University, Records and Reports
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Administrative records, 1963-1980; Accession 1980-A-014
  - 78R004: OIR. Yale College Course Registrations by Division and Department, 1967-68 to 1975-77. [lacking], 1978 February 1 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - 78ROOS: Hackman, J. D. et al. The Yale College Experience and Post-College Planning., 1978 January 1 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - 78R006: Goldin, J.R. Counting the Faculty., 1978 February 1 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Supplement: Goldin, J.R. Authorized Teaching Positions in the Faculty of Arts and Science 1974-75 to 1977-78., 1978 September 1 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - 78R007: Goldin, J. R., Suttle, J.L. Yale College Class Size, 1978 February 1 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - 78R008: OIR. Yale Graduate School Fall Enrollment by Division and Department, 1967-68 to 1976-77. [lacking], 1978 February 1 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - 78R009: OIR. Yale Graduate School Course Registration by Divisions and Departments, 1967-68 to 1976-77. [lacking], 1978 February 1 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - 78R010: Hackman, J.D. et al. The Pre-med Stereotype., 1978 March 17 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - 78RD11: Goldin, J.R. Transfer of Admissions Data to the Yale College Registar., 1978 June 1 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - 78R012: OIR. Yale College Fall Term Grades 1977-78., 1978 June 15 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - 78R013: Hackman, J.D. Analysis of Graduate Student Life Questionnaire., 1978 February 19 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - 78R014: Hackman, J.D. Analysis of Professional Student Life Questionnaire. [not included], 1978 March 19 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - 78R015: Hackman, J.D. The Special Student Program: A Reviw of the First Year (Summary Report)., 1978 July 1 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - 78R016: Hackman, J.D. The Special Student Program: A Reviw of the First Year, 1978 October 1 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - 78R017: OIR. Faculty, Staff, and Students in Yale University, 1978 April 1 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - : A. Full Time Equivalent Faculty and Staff, 1974-1978 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - : B. Student Enrollment by School and Program, 1973-1978 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - : C. Degrees Awarded by School and Program, 1973-1978 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - : D. Majors in Yale College, 1967-1977 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - : E. Yale College Course Registrations by Division/Department, 1967-1977 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - : F. Graduate School Enrollment by Division/Department, 1967-1977 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - : G. Graduate School Course Registrations by Division/Department, 1967-1977 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - 78R018: Goldin, J.R. Study on Alumni Giving and the Yale Alumni Fund., 1978 October 1 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - 78R019: Suttle, J.L. Budget Planning Analyses: Torm Bill Income and Student Aid Expenditures, 1978 July 28 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - 78R020: OIR. Yale College Spring Term Grades 1977-1978., 1978 August 1 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - 78R021: Goldin, J.R.Users Manual: Yale Budget Model [lacking], 1978 August 1 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - 78R022: Goldin, J.R.Financial Aid in Yale College (Brainard), 1978 June 21 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - 78R023: Supplement, 1978 August 25 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - 78R024: Goldin, J.R., and Suttle, J.L. Enrollment Related Income and Expense., 1978 October 11 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - 78R025: Suttle, J.L. Yale College Financial Aid Records., 1978 November 7 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - 78R026: Suttle, J.L. Make-Up Examinations in Yale College., 1978 December 4 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - 78R027: Suttle, J.L., and Mcmanus, F. Ben. Housing in the Residential Colleges., 1978 December 1 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - 78R028: Suttle, J.L., and Hawthorne, D.D. Designing a User-Oriented Student Records System., 1978 December 1 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - 78R029: Waters, B.W. Teaching Awards Granted at Selected Colleges and Universities., 1978 December 15 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - 78R030: Ackerman, J.R., and Goldin, J.R. The Yale Financial Model: An Application of EFPM., 1978 November 9 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - 78R03l: Goldin, J.R. BEOG Forecast., 1979 March 1 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - 78R032: Suttle, J.L. Religious Preferences of Students in Yale College and the Graduate and Professional Schools, 1979 March 1 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - 78R033: Suttle, J.L. Student-Faculty Ratios at Yale,Harvard and Princeton., 1979 May 7 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - 78R034: OIR (Series). The Yale College Class of 1977: Its Current Activities., 1979 June 1 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - 78R035: Suttle, J.L. Student Enrollment in Yale University 1967-1968 to 1978-1979. [lacking], 1979 July 16 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - 78R036: Suttle, J.L. Schedules of Large Undergraduate Classes and Classrooms., 1978 November 16 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - 79R001: OIR. Yale College Fall Term Grades 1978-1979., 1979 August 1 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - 79R002: OIR. Yale College Spring Term Grades 1978-79. [lacking], 1979 August 1 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - 79R003: Suttle, J.L., and Risberg, R. Predicting Grades in Yale Law School., 1979 October 1 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - 79R004: Waters, B. Women at Yale: A Statistical Profile, 1969-1979., 1979 October 1 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - 79R005: Hackman, Judith D. Fall Enrollment. Tuition F.T.E.'s and Income at Yale University, 1979-1980., 1979 October 26 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - 79R006: Suttle, J.L. and Goldin, J.R. Restructuring Yale's Student Information Systems., 1979 March 26 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - 79R007: Suttle, J. Lloyd. A Framework for Examining Yale College Admissions and Financial Aid Policies. [not included], 1979 November 26 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - 79R008: OIR. Yale Admissions Statistics, 1979-1980., 1979 November 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 79R009: Goldin, John. Information on Faculty Compensation at Yale and at Other Institutions., 1979 November 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 79R010: Suttle, J. Lloyd. The Rising Cost of a Yale College Education: Recent Trends in Term Bill Rates and Term Bill Income., 1979 November 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 79R011: OIR (Series). The Yale College Class of 1978: Its Current Activities. [not included], 1900 January 0 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 79R012: OIR (Series). The Yale College Class of 1978: Its Current Activities. [not included], 1979 December 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 79R013: Hackman, Judith D. Special, Summer, Outreach and Visiting Programs at Yale., 1979 December 14 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 80R001: Suttle, J. Lloyd. Budgeting Student Aid Expenditures in Yale College: A Report to the University Budget Committee., 1980 January (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Grade reports, 1963-1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Grade reports, 1970-1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Grade reports, 1974-1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Senior Studies, 1968-1972 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Senior Studies, 1973-1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Factbook, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Administrative records, 1949-1982; Accession 1983-A-038
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2017
  - OIR Reports, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 2)
  - Miscellaneous Sternberg Reports, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - OIR Reports, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4 - 7)
  - OIR Reports, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8 - 10)
  - Budget (and Personnel), 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Budget (and Personnel), 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Budget Fiscal Year (and Personnel), 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Questionnaires, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - FAS Department 5-Year Plans, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 15 - 18)
  - Department Curricula Other Universities, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 19 - 21)
  - FAS Departmental Indicators: planning and correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - FAS Departments' Reports Academic Planning, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - February 1975, "Survey of Undergraduate plans (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Sunmer Term Survey, 1974 April (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Summer Term Committee, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 26 - 27)
  - Summer Programs, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - The Selective College, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Science Students, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Undergraduate Admissions Research Committee, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Yale Sons, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous Admissions Research, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Comparison of Admissions Variables, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Matriculant Classes Data, 1958-1974 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Criteria of College Success, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - The Independence of Abilities, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Athletes, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Bibliography, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - EPIC, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Introduction, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Policy, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Normative Nodel, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Criteria of a "Successful" Admissions Program, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Admit - Withdrawl, undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Interviews, undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Decision Rule, undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Admissions Criteria, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Notes on old B.P.'s, 1968-1976 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Miscellaneous Studies, etc. (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Coding Information (Box 2)
  - Old correspondence and office memos (Box 2)
  - Yale Letter Grade (RJ) Equivalent for Yale Numerical Grades 4172
  - Campaign for Yale, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Drafts, undated (Box 2, Folder 51 - 54)
  - Dahl Committee Records "Study Group on Yale College", 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - FTE Gaculty and Teaching Loads (Hoskins, 76R010 and earlier), 1969-1976 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Hoskins, Teaching Fellows, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Hoskins, Educational Load Statistics - Reports and workpapers [See also: Taylor, Bockelman and Goldin files], 1970-1977 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Budget Analyses: Term Bill Income and Student Aid Expenditures (Extra copies of miscellaneous OIR tables and reports), 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Budget Analyses: Term Bill Income and Student Aid Expenditures, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - University of Toronto Statistics, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Taylor, Educational Load Statistics, (1-6), 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Council on Priorities and Planning (1/16/1978 Meeting) Financial, Enrollment, Degree, and Faculty Statistics, 1973-1978 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Bockelman: 1972-1973 Educational Load Statistics Departments and Selected Hurnanity and Social Science Departments, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Graduate School Enrollment By course (and Hoskins Statistics), 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Academic and Auxilliary Income (Application Fee Income), 1978 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Class size, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Academic Department Expenditures, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - University Catalogue Nmber, Enrollment, Degrees, and Staff Counts, 1968-1975 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - ACE Reports, 1958-1975 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - ACE Survey #19 Fall 1973 Enrollment of Minority Graduate Students (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - ACE Survey #26 Enrollment of Junior-Year Students by Major Field, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Undergraduate Course Registrations, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Minority Student Transcripts for Dahl Committee Report, 4 (Box 7)
  - HEGIS Reports, 1971-1974 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - HEGIS, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - YGS Candidates for Degrees, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Information for HEGIS reports, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - HEGIS - Degrees and other Formal conferred, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - HEGIS, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Yale College Title IX Data,Fall 1974 OIR75R001, January 1975 (NBL), 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Old Correspondence, J. Hackman, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - NEASC Reaccreditation #2, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - NEASC Reaccreditation #1 Working Papers, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 83 - 84)
    - Science Evaluation Committee, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - Arts Evaluation Committee, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Social Science Evaluation Committee, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Writing Study, Freshmen 1975-1976, 1976-1978 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Admissions and Criteria Study, -1976 (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - Carnegie Council Survey, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Special Student Program Evaluation Papers, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - Governance Commission, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Dahl Committee, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Blum Committee on Future of the College and Graduate School, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Admissions Pre-Class of 1979, Yale College (Box 5, Folder 95)
  - Admissions forms Yale College, 1971-1981 (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - University Organization and Appointments, 1971-1977 (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - Admissions Profiles Yale College Classes 76, 1972-1976 (Box 5, Folder 98)
  - Admissions analyses Pre-class of 1979 Yale College, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 99)
  - OER Reports, 1966-67 (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - Acceleration and Advanced Placements, Class 1976 (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - Research Proposal Submitted to NIE Grants for Research in Education, 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - Thirty Year Follow-up of Male College Students, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - Development and Application of Tests for University Students in Norway: A Report on Parts of a Research Project - 13 copies, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - Relationship of Successful and Unsuccessful Types to Quantified Admissions Variables, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - Biannual Report on College Grades, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - Procedures and Applications for the Statistical Analysis of Yale College Admissions Data, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 107)
  - Enrollment, Admissions, and the Sumer Term, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 108)
  - Completion of HEGIS and Title IX Forms using SPSS, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 109)
  - Attendance Patterns and Graduation Credits for the Yale College Class of 1973 (Box 6, Folder 110)
  - Profiles of Yale College, undated (Box 6, Folder 112)
  - Faculty Handbook, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 113)
  - College Criteria Study - Prestudy Report #1, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 114)
  - Timothy Dwight College Seminar Project, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 116)
  - Leave - Return Study Codes, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 117)
  - Ma-Mi ADC Class of 1963 Alumni Children, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 118)
  - Campaign for Yale - Scholarship Study - Alumni (Box 6, Folder 120)
  - Criteria Study Layout and Codes, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 121)
  - List of Sons and Daughters Currently Enrolled in Yale College, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 122)
  - Attendance Patterns and Graduation Credits for the Yale College Class of 1973 (Box 6, Folder 123)
  - Master and Copies for SAT Distributions, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 124)
  - Presidency - Credits Study - Classes of 1974 and 1975, and Transfers 4/17/1975, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 125)
  - Residency Study Yale College 8/30/74 Class of 1974 - Matriculants, transfers Copy Final Report, and Working Papers (Box 6, Folder 126)
  - Hewitt Occupational Code 2 Digit Code, 1962 December 12 (Box 6, Folder 127)
  - Educational Testing Service, 1965 August 19 (Box 6, Folder 128)
  - College Code used on RP 407 - Graduate Study, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 129)
  - PP 408 Codes - Yale Graduate School Alumni Questionnaire, 1967 July (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - Research in Undergraduate Athletics - Ernie McGowan, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - Admit - Withdraw Class of 1975 (Box 6, Folder 132)
  - Admit/withdraw Study - Class of 1975, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 133)
  - Admit - Withdraw Study Codes - Class of 1976, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 134)
  - Backup Documents and Information for Admissions Data Analysis Project (OIR 74R012) (JLS), 1974 (Box 6, Folder 135)
  - Transfer and Special Students - Work Papers, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 136)
  - Yale Sons and Daughters, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 137)
  - Henry Chauncey, 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 138)
  - General correspondence FISCAL YEAR 1977 (JHH) (Box 7, Folder 139)
  - General correspondence (JLS), 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 140)
  - Name Change List, 1973-1982 (Box 7, Folder 141)
  - 781 "Kiddie Book", 1978 January 1 (Box 7, Folder 142 - 143)
  - Chemistry Department Placement Study, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 144)
  - Full Time FAS Ladder Faculty by Yale and Columbia Definitions (reductions o f computer printouts), 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 145)
  - NSF Reports: personnel, 1971-1980 (Box 7, Folder 146)
  - 1976-1977 Affirmative Action Statistics, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 147)
  - Faculty Administrators, 1973-1977 (Box 7, Folder 148)
  - Faculty Leaves, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 149)
  - FAS Faculty, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 150)
  - Administrative Science Program, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 151)
  - 1969-1970 Faculty F.T.E.'s - 5-year Average of Death and Resignations f o r Faculty, 1974-1979 (Box 7, Folder 152)
  - Graduate School Departmental Survey, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 153)
  - OER Bursary Students and Employees, 1949-1964 (Box 7, Folder 154 - 155)
  - OIR Employees and Bursary Students, 1971-1978 (Box 7, Folder 156)
  - Questionnaires, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 157)
  - Graduate School Financial Aid: Financial Aid Study (working papers) - Graduate School, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 158)
  - BEOG Projection - Yale College Financial Aid, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 159)
  - CBS Analyses - Yale College Financial Aid, 1973-1975 (Box 7, Folder 160)
  - Faculty Survey on Fringe Benefits -Nordhaus/ Ryerson Committees - Working Papers, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 161 - 163)
  - Fringe Benefit Survey Summaries, 1980 January (Box 8, Folder 164)
  - ACE/CIRP Survey
    - Class of 1975, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 165)
    - Class pf 1976, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 166)
    - Class of 1977, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 167)
    - Class of 1978, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 168)
    - Class of 1979, 195 (Box 8, Folder 169)
  - Publications:
    - The American Freshman National Norms for Fall 1977 (Box 8, Folder 170)
    - The American Freshman: National Norms for Fall 1971" (Box 8)
    - The American Freshman: National Norms for Fall 1973" (Box 8)
  - Summer term 1977 alout Listing (N=591) (Includes 4 visiting students who withdrew before 6/8, but excludes 2 Yale Registered students) (Box 8, Folder 171)
  - "EPIC" Materials-- on Undergraduate-Admissions., 1969-1975 (Box 8, Folder 172 - 173)
  - Summer Term Evaluation Committee (Appointments, Meetings, Letters etc.), 1974-1978 (Box 8, Folder 174)
  - Summer Term Evaluation Design, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 175)
  - Preliminary Report on the 1975 Summer Term (2/20/1976 Report to S.T.E.C.) (Box 8, Folder 176)
  - Applications and Publicity, 1975-1978 (Box 8, Folder 178)
  - Student Lists, 1975-1977 (Box 8, Folder 179)
  - Surveys of Student Reactions - Summer Term Coding Sheets, Printouts etc, 1975-1977 (Box 8, Folder 180 - 181)
  - Summer Term Courses (Enrollments, Graduates, Program of Study), 1975-1978 (Box 8, Folder 182)
  - Ford Proposaf/Coopers and Lybrand (Enrollment Planning Model), 1974 (Box 9, Folder 183)
  - Survey of Reasons for NOT Attending the Summer Term, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 184)
  - Survey of "Reasons for Attending the 1976 Summer Term" (Box 9, Folder 185)
  - CFAE Reports, 1956-1978 (Box 9, Folder 186)
  - OIR76R008 Grade Study Fall, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 187)
  - OIR76R009 Grade Study Fall, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 188 - 189)
  - OIR74R002 Grade Study Fall Term, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 190)
  - OIR74002 Grade Study Spring Term, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 191)
  - OIR75R002 Grade Study Fall Term, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 192)
  - OIR 75R007 Grade Study Spring, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 193)
  - Senior Study, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 194 - 195)
  - Codes for Senior Study - Class of 1971-1972 and 1974, 1972 July (Box 9, Folder 196)
  - Senior Study Class of 1972 (Box 9, Folder 197)
  - Senior Study Class of 1971-1972; R014, 1971 November (Box 9, Folder 198)
  - Senior Study Program, 1973 August (Box 9, Folder 199)
  - Senior Survey Class of 1974 (Box 9, Folder 200)
  - Senior Study - Class of 1975 - Code Sheets (Box 10, Folder 201)
  - Senior Study - working papers, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 202)
  - Athlete Study, 1980 Spring (Box 10, Folder 203 - 204)
  - Codes Used for RP466 Senior Questions (including College Codes), 1966 July 10 (Box 10, Folder 205)
  - Senior Study Codes (Xerox and originals), 1971 October (Box 10, Folder 206)
  - Senior Survey Tables 1 through 15B - Working Papers - Class of 1971 (Box 10, Folder 207)
- Records pertaining to affirmative action and the Yale Fact Book, 1978-1982; Accession 1984-A-022
  - Affirmative Action Plan, Yale University, 1980
    - Women and Minorities (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Appendices (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Attachments (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Handicapped (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Veterans (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Departmental Statistics, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 7)
  - Factbook on Yale University, 1982
    - Table of Contents (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - University-wide
      - Faculty/staff (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Students (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Other (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Faculty of Arts and Sciences
      - Faculty (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Departments (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Yale College (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Graduate School (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Professional Schools
      - Architecture (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Art (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Divinity (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Drama (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Forestry (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Law (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Medicine - Epidemiology and Public Health (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Medicine - M.D. (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Medicine - Physician Associate Program (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Music (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Nursing (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - School of Organization and Management (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Faculty course list, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Report of the Senior Profile Study, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Yale University Fact Book and report on Yale tuition, 1982-1984; Accession 1984-A-023
  - Yale University Fact Book, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 4)
  - "Paying for a Yale Education: Report of the Provost's Task Force on Trends and Prospects in Tuition, Enrollment, and Student Aid", 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Administrative records, 1971-1980; Accession 1985-A-013
  - EDUCOM Financial Planning Model
    - Background material, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Budget calculations and misc. working papers, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Budget model, 1978 October-November (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Computer listings, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 4 - 5)
    - Correspondence, 1978-October-December (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Profile of Yale College Students
    - Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Pre-study Reports
      - #1, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - #2, 1973 July 6 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - #3-4, 1973 July 12 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Publications ordered, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Purchase orders and invoices, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Reports, correspondence, and memos
      - 1971 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - 1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - 1973 (Box 2, Folder 15 - 16)
      - 1974 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - 1975 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - 1976 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - 1977 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Research reports and correspondence, 1955-1984; Accession 1987-A-019
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2019
  - Research Reports and Materials
    - Study of Students of Uniformly High Ability; RP 326, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abstract of the Study of Undergraduates of Uniformly High Ability; RP 326, 1960 June 30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Comparative Study of Groton School Students in Yale Classes; RP 327, 1938-1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Advanced Placement Exam Scores - College Board Entrance Exam Study; RP 330, 1963, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Advanced Placement Study; RP 330 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - A Study of Students Who Have Shown Academic Improvement; RP 334, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 30-year Follow-up: Reference and Miscellaneous material; RP 335B, 1964 September - December (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 30-year Follow-up: Contracts; RP 335B, 1964 September - December (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 30-year Follow-up: Financial Status Report; RP 335B (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Validity of Predictors over 3 Decades (Pearson); RP 335C (Box 1, Folder 10)